<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Macplugins</title><description>Very infrequent posts about my side projects.</description><link>https://endresjd.github.io</link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 09:27:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 09:27:39 -0500</pubDate><ttl>250</ttl><atom:link href="https://endresjd.github.io/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://endresjd.github.io/cornyjokes/10</guid><title>Corny Jokes 1.0 released!</title><description>An experiment with Claude</description><link>https://endresjd.github.io/cornyjokes/10</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 09:27:34 -0500</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Corny Jokes 1.0 released!</h1><ul><li>With all the care I usually put into a release, with bare-bones screen shots!</li><li>Get it here: <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/corny-jokes/id6757873673">Corny Jokes</a></li></ul>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://endresjd.github.io/fortune/liquidglassupdate</guid><title>Liquid Glass Update</title><description>New Fortune release</description><link>https://endresjd.github.io/fortune/liquidglassupdate</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 21:17:42 -0500</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>New Fortune release</h1><ul><li>I'd let this sit too long, and it was delisted.</li><li>This was an update I did during the iOS 26 beta period and then forgot again.</li><li>I found some new fortune files randomly and included them here</li></ul>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://endresjd.github.io/cornyjokes/newappblurb</guid><title>A new app in the making</title><description>An experiment with Claude</description><link>https://endresjd.github.io/cornyjokes/newappblurb</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:57:07 -0500</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>A new app in the making</h1><ul><li>A tiny app to see how much of the grind work I could get done using something like Claude that came out of giving a talk about using Claude to my CocoaHeads group.</li><li>I found some public APIs, and chose one. <a href="https://www.freepublicapis.com/official-joke-api">Official Joke API</a></li><li>If it passes final review, I'll publish it. For now I wanted it to have a dedicated privacy policy page.</li></ul><h2>What did I have Claude do?</h2><ol><li>Generate an app by giving the link to the actual published API</li><li>Clean up and document the code.</li><li>Make sure all the views had proper Previews</li><li>Made sure all model code had proper tests.</li></ol><h2>What did I do?</h2><ol><li>I spent most of my time refining a skill file so that the code generated or modified met my style and readability guidelines.</li><li>Changed the view it generated slightly so it supported dynamic text, so that it has the minimum accessibility that I at least expect.</li><li>Pushed it through TestFlight to my CocoaHeads group and a few other people and saw an appreciation for the truly bad jokes coming out. Especially the programming ones.</li><li>Realized I hadn't done anything to this website in years. So had to update it.</li></ol>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://endresjd.github.io/cornyjokes/privacy</guid><title>Privacy policy</title><description>Privacy Policy for Corny Jokes</description><link>https://endresjd.github.io/cornyjokes/privacy</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:34:52 -0500</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="center">
    <img src="https://endresjd.github.io/images/cornyjoke.png" width="120" max-width="90%" alt="Corny Jokes" />

    <h1 align="center">Corny Jokes</h1>
</p><h1>Privacy policy</h1><p>Macplugins built the Corny Jokes app as a Commercial app. This SERVICE is provided by Macplugins and is intended for use as is. This page is used to inform users regarding my policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use my Service.</p><h2>Information Collection and Use</h2><p>Corny Jokes DOES NOT collect, transmit, or store any data. Period.</p><h2>Changes to This Privacy Policy</h2><p>I may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. Thus, you are advised to review this page periodically for any changes. I will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page. These changes are effective immediately after they are posted on this page.</p><h2>Contact Us</h2><p>If you have any questions or suggestions about my Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact me at support@macplugins.com.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://endresjd.github.io/wordtiles/privacy</guid><title>Privacy policy</title><description>Privacy Policy for WordTiles</description><link>https://endresjd.github.io/wordtiles/privacy</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 12:43:18 -0400</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="center">
    <img src="https://endresjd.github.io/images/wordtiles.png" width="120" max-width="90%" alt="WordTiles" />

    <h1 align="center"> WordTiles </h1>
</p><h1>Privacy policy</h1><p>Macplugins built the WordTiles app as a Commercial app. This SERVICE is provided by Macplugins and is intended for use as is. This page is used to inform users regarding my policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use my Service.</p><h2>Information Collection and Use</h2><p>WordTiles DOES NOT collect, transmit, or store any data. Period.</p><h2>Changes to This Privacy Policy</h2><p>I may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. Thus, you are advised to review this page periodically for any changes. I will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page. These changes are effective immediately after they are posted on this page.</p><h2>Contact Us</h2><p>If you have any questions or suggestions about my Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact me at support@macplugins.com.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://endresjd.github.io/rot13/privacy</guid><title>Privacy policy</title><description>Privacy Policy for Rot13</description><link>https://endresjd.github.io/rot13/privacy</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 12:43:18 -0400</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="center">
    <img src="https://endresjd.github.io/images/rot13.png" width="120" max-width="90%" alt="Rot13" />

    <h1 align="center">Rot13</h1>
</p><h1>Privacy policy</h1><p>MacPlugins built the Rot13 app as a Commercial app. This SERVICE is provided by MacPlugins and is intended for use as is. This page is used to inform users regarding my policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use my Service.</p><h2>Information Collection and Use</h2><p>Rot13 DOES NOT collect, transmit, or store any data. Period.</p><h2>Changes to This Privacy Policy</h2><p>I may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. Thus, you are advised to review the privacy policy on my support page periodically for any changes. I will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on that page. These changes are effective immediately after they are posted on this page.</p><h2>Contact Us</h2><p>If you have any questions or suggestions about my Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact me at support@macplugins.com.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://endresjd.github.io/posts/newwebsite</guid><title>New website (using Publish)</title><description>New website.</description><link>https://endresjd.github.io/posts/newwebsite</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 12:43:18 -0400</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>New website (using Publish)</h1><p>The web site I have to provide information required by my mobile apps is very simple, but I did not like dealing with HTML or web site generators online. Too difficult for me given what little I have to offer on a web site. When I found John Sundell's Publish tool, I decided to play around with that. It let me focus on what little content I have, notably privacy policies, in a way that is more familiar. Markdown files. So this web site is now generated from a Swift package and updated as needed with my hosting provider.</p><h2>Publish</h2><p>Publish is a static site generator built specifically for Swift developers -- his words. My needs are simple and my updates rare, this lets me put things together using a collection of Markdown files that include hints in them to help Publish generate the website. Here's a link to the project he published: <a href="https://github.com/JohnSundell/Publish">Publish</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://endresjd.github.io/fortune/privacy</guid><title>Privacy policy</title><description>Privacy Policy for Fortune 3.0</description><link>https://endresjd.github.io/fortune/privacy</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 12:43:18 -0400</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="center">
    <img src="https://endresjd.github.io/images/fortune.png" width="120" max-width="90%" alt="Fortune" />

    <h1 align="center">Fortune</h1>
</p><h1>Privacy policy</h1><p>Macplugins built the Fortune app as a Commercial app. This SERVICE is provided by Macplugins and is intended for use as is. This page is used to inform users regarding my policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use my Service.</p><h2>Information Collection and Use</h2><p>Fortune DOES NOT collect, transmit, or store any data. Period.</p><h2>Changes to This Privacy Policy</h2><p>I may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. Thus, you are advised to review this page periodically for any changes. I will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page. These changes are effective immediately after they are posted on this page.</p><h2>Contact Us</h2><p>If you have any questions or suggestions about my Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact me at support@macplugins.com.</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>